[Episode 6]
[A Bright Mirror Hung High]
I, Meng Ting Hui, accuse Huiyuan An Ru Lan
of stealing my policy essay.
I beg you, Prefect, to deliver justice.
Confucius said,
"Think thrice before you act."
Then he added, "Twice is sufficient."
You spread this essay across the capital,
causing a huge uproar.
Do you have any proof?
You can summon An Ru Lan
to court for a confrontation.
Prefect, she gathered all those commoners
outside here.
Summon Huiyuan An.
I'm Huiyuan An Ru Lan. Greetings, Prefect.
Huiyuan An, no need for such formalities.
The seat for the Huiyuan is ready.
Please be seated.
Jiang Mei Er, what are you doing here?
Second Master,
it was that wretch, Meng Ting Hui.
She harmed my uncle and Mr. Feng.
I wish I could tear her flesh
and sleep on her hide.
Where is she now?
She won the top candidate and will soon
head to the capital for the exams.
I have a way to deal with her.
Second Master, by helping me,
you'll be ridding Master of a true menace,
which is a great deed.
As long as you help me,
I will be yours.
This fellow student is talking nonsense.
Have you lost your mind?
Prefect, please judge fairly.
This woman's real name is Jiang Mei Er.
She is the niece
of the former Governor of Shazhou.
She was my classmate
at the Shazhou Women's Academy.
Back in Shazhou, she never studied,
acting tyrannically
and bullying our classmates.
She might deny it
now that she has changed her name,
but since she won the Huiyuan title,
she must have real knowledge.
Prefect, I request to debate the classics
with Huiyuan An on the spot.
Why have you all come here today,
if not to seek justice?
Then let us all see together
how much real knowledge this Huiyuan
of the Imperial Exam for Women
actually possesses.
Well said!
- We want to see real knowledge!
- Real knowledge!
We want to see real knowledge!
Good. I, too, favor those
with real knowledge.
When a nation prospers,
it tends to its people as wounded.
That is its blessing.
When it perishes,
it treats the people as dirt and weeds.
That is its ruin.
Does this quote come from the Book of Rites
or the Book of Documents?
It is the Book of Rites.
No, it's the Book of Documents.
It's the Zuo Commentary.
I just misremembered. That's all.
What can these few words prove?
Did you all hear that clearly?
It's a classic text that all scholars
in the world know,
yet she quibbles,
saying she misremembered it.
How could such a contradictory person
be the Huiyuan?
Has the Ning Empire's Imperial Exam
become a child's game?
Well said!
Prefect, the Huiyuan's policy essay
was not written by her at all.
I beg you to judge fairly.
Confucius said, "Knowing that you know--"
Prefect,
after ten years of hard study,
I finally achieved scholarly rank.
And now she's framed me like this.
You must uphold justice.
Confucius said: "Watch a man's actions,
examine his motives--"
Prefect, she insists the Huiyuan's essay
came from her own hand,
then why not retest her
on this essay right now?
I'll take the test with her right here.
One test will tell the truth from the lie.
Prefect, there is no need for a test.
In black and white, I wrote the essay.
There is no mistake.
Can you both let me finish speaking?
All this commotion is hardly proper.
And this isn't the exam hall.
What's there to test?
Do you really think that scholarly rank
can be twisted by a glib tongue?
Jiang Mei Er,
I got rid of your uncle.
You really think I can't do the same to you?
You did not see how terribly your uncle died.
A bolt to the heart, he died on the spot.
Let me guess
how you stole my Huiyuan title.
Was it through your uncle's
pitiful connections,
or
did you make some shady deal?
What you always care about most is your face.
You boast of being the foremost beauty.
Could it be that you relied on...
As long as you help me,
I will be yours.
Shut your mouth!
Meng Ting Hui!
Order! Order!
Madwoman!
The trial is not over yet!
Pull them apart! Court adjourned! Adjourned!
Meng Ting Hui!
You took everything from me.
I will kill you!
Prefect, did you hear it clearly?
Is the truth not clear enough?
Guards,
seize this fake Huiyuan
who has deceived the world.
So you're all birds of a feather,
colluding in evil.
In the Imperial Exam world,
in the court of law,
all I see are wolves
that devour people without mercy.
Now you've finally figured it out.
What a pity, it is far too late.
Did you really think
those ignorant commoners could help you?
In the end, you still fell into my hands.
From now on,
in the Imperial Exam for Women,
there will be no Meng Ting Hui anymore.
In this world,
the shameless
live longer than the reckless.
Meng Ting Hui,
whether in Shazhou or the capital,
I can easily destroy anything you cherish.
I can destroy it!
- Let go of me!
- Pull them apart!
If I go down, you're coming with me!
You disgrace scholarly decorum
in this very court!
Confucius said, "Harmony is the essence
of proper conduct."
Jieyuan Meng,
you'd better confess
to the crime of falsely accusing the Huiyuan.
I guarantee your life will be spared.
Prefect, she has stirred up such a huge mess
and nearly took my life.
She must not be spared.
Everyone already knows
about the real and fake Huiyuan.
If something happens to me,
it will only confirm
the truth of my accusation.
Then will you still be able
to stay out of it, Prefect?
Turn back now,
and you might still save your life.
What a glib tongue.
Prefect, arrest her immediately.
Confucius said, "Do not govern
where you do not hold office."
I have my own sense
of how to handle this case.
No need for you to say more.
Throw her in prison.
Prefect, the Huxiao Gang is here.
Second Master Lv and Huiyuan An.
Come over here.
Prefect Dong, how do you plan
to deal with Meng Ting Hui?
I've already made arrangements.
I'll spread the word that Meng Ting Hui
lost her mind after failing the exam
and lock her up for a while.
Once the dust settles,
I'll send her back to Shazhou.
You're truly a good official.
You flatter me, Huiyuan An.
I believe
that if we kill Meng Ting Hui,
it'll definitely cause a stir.
I am doing this for the bigger picture.
Second Master, look.
He does not take you seriously at all.
He is leaving himself a way out.
Mei Er, rest assured.
I've invited Prefect Dong's wife and children
for tea at the teahouse.
W-Why did you do that?
I have done as you instructed.
What else do you want from me?
I want to see Master.
Master?
Do you look down on me?
Dong Shou Cai, without the Huxiao Gang,
you wouldn't be wearing this robe.
How dare you put on airs in front of me?
Do not forget,
you haven't repaid
the court official debt yet.
If Master finds out, you're as good as dead.
So, Prefect, you'd better think carefully.
Do you want glory and wealth
or a torn-apart family?
I'll leave it all to you two,
Second Master and Huiyuan An.
All who participated
in the Imperial Exam fraud
are to be detained pending trial.
As you command.
Take them away!
Your Majesty, Zhi Li instructed me
to present this item urgently.
It's a grievance petition
written personally by Meng Ting Hui herself.
Countless copies have been made
and spread across the capital's streets.
[Petition of Grievance]
She has lit this fire swiftly and fiercely.
Where is she now?
Capital Prefectural Office.
To the Capital Prefectural Office.
Jiang Mei Er,
you had better kill me today,
or I will make your life worse than death.
Killing you now?
How boring that would be.
I want to torment you to death, bit by bit.
I will make you repay ten thousandfold.
Anything else you want to say?
You deserved it.
You shall die a thousand deaths.
You will get your comeuppance
sooner or later.
Her false accusation failed,
so she took her own life.
She burned the prison, and died in flames.
Understood?
Yes.
Still trying to run?
Meng Ting Hui,
you got over a hundred
of my Heihu Crew brothers killed.
Today, you will join them in death!
Meng Ting Hui!
Meng Ting Hui,
since fire cannot kill you,
I will finish you off with my own hands.
Fall back!
Meng Ting Hui, you madwoman!
She is there!
I will kill you!
Let's go!
Get them!
He Du, they tried to kill me.
Leave it to me.
I, Dong Shou Cai,
studied hard for ten years
and held myself to the ways of the sages.
On the day I passed the Imperial Exam,
I also swore before the mirror
to be an honest official.
Yet I faltered
and strayed from the right path.
I was timid and cautious for half my life.
I deserve punishment for my sins,
and I deeply regret it.
I'm willing to atone with my death.
But my family is innocent.
I beg Your Majesty
to show mercy.
[Laws of Ning Empire]
Miss Meng.
Huiyuan Meng is nothing
but a common orphan girl.
How did she get His Majesty
to personally intervene on her behalf?
[Nine Nine Nine]
Many noble ladies from powerful families
are eagerly longing for His Majesty's favor,
yet they cannot even get a proper glance.
But he pays her so much attention?
His Majesty values the Imperial Exam.
This is the first Imperial Exam
since His Majesty ascended the throne,
yet it has encountered such fraud.
His Majesty's action is a declaration
of his resolve to the realm.
But she had no reason to enter the palace.
Ever since His Majesty was a child,
except for you, no other woman
has ever been allowed to stay in the palace.
I fear that she wants to stay
in the palace for good.
After all, that's much easier
than the Imperial Exam.
He Du!
Miss Meng.
It's you.
Where am I?
Can you not see?
This is the imperial palace.
Right, I was just about to ask you,
what exactly happened
between you and His Majesty in Shazhou?
Chief Eunuch You,
I heard His Majesty say he wanted some soup
as I was leaving.
Hurry back and check on him.
Alright.
Miss Meng, you are finally awake.
His Majesty saved you.
You've been unconscious for two days,
and your fever would not break.
Are you feeling better now?
The imperial physician prescribed this
to fortify you and clear the heat.
Drink it while it is warm.
He is actually the emperor?
I never thought after that hurried meeting
at the exam hall entrance,
we would meet again today in the palace.
Thank you for taking care of me.
No need for formalities.
On the day of the Metropolitan Exam,
I thought I could win the top spot.
I never imagined
there were greater peaks beyond.
After reading your policy essay through,
I could not sleep at night,
only hoping to meet the author soon.
I never imagined it would be you, Miss Meng.
I am truly delighted in my heart.
Miss, do you know how Miss Yan is doing now?
Rest assured, Miss Yan has been sent back
to Chunman House.
All is well.
Drink it while it is warm.
Hearing what happened to you,
I still feel lingering fear even now.
Good thing you fought back so well,
so they did not succeed.
Now it is all good.
His Majesty not only
restored your title as Huiyuan
but also threw Jiang Mei Er into prison.
It is truly gratifying.
Has His Majesty come by these days?
Not yet.
With such a huge matter happening,
His Majesty is very busy.
But he instructed me
to take good care of you.
Then may I go and see His Majesty?
You should rest and recover first.
If there is anything,
I can help convey it for you.
I want to go to the Ministry of Justice.
Imperial Guard Huang.
Imperial Guard Huang,
I want to speak with her alone.
Speak. How did you hook up with Lv,
bribe the examiners,
and set the fire to kill me?
You are not much better than me.
You're only standing here because you climbed
onto His Majesty's bed.
Without a man, you are nothing.
Meng Ting Hui,
you are still so arrogant
and so self-righteous.
Do you know what I hate most about you?
It is those eyes of yours.
You're merely a lowly wretch with no parents.
What gives you the right
to look at me like that?
I, Jiang Mei Er,
come from a prestigious family
with stunning beauty.
I could have had boundless glory.
But you've ruined it all.
You forced me... forced me to have no choice
but to eliminate you.
To what extent do you want to destroy me?
The one who destroyed you
has always been yourself.
You acted lawlessly
because of your family background.
You held power in your hands,
yet all you did was oppress the innocent.
It was your jealousy, greed, and obsession
that pushed you into the abyss.
Confess truthfully,
and your sentence may be reduced.
But you only get one chance.
Meng Ting Hui, do you dare say
you have no ambition?
Do you dare say you do not want to climb up?
Deep down, we are the same.
You are just better at pretending than I am.
Now you hypocritically say you will spare me?
Do you even believe the nonsense yourself?
We have never been the same.
But you are right about one thing.
I do want to climb up.
And now, I have reached a position
where I can decide your fate.
You won't write it?
Since you do not want the chance,
forget it.
Meng Ting Hui, I will write it.
I will write it.
As long as you spare me,
I will do anything.
My mother said
that I must survive.
I must survive.
Only by surviving can everything begin anew.
[Condemned Woman Jiang Mei Er, Shazhou]
I must survive.
The second-in-command of the Huxiao Gang,
known as Second Master Lv.
The Heihu Crew in Shazhou
was just a branch of the Huxiao Gang.
I have confessed everything.
You said the sentence would be reduced.
Yes.
Your heinous crimes
warranted death by a thousand cuts.
His Majesty now grants you a swift death,
which is already the greatest mercy.
Meng Ting Hui!
I was wrong!
I beg you!
I beg you! I beg you!
- Jiang Mei Er.
- Spare me!
I came today to send you off
on your final journey.
Although I... although I have harmed you,
aren't you standing here perfectly fine now?
And you've even caught His Majesty's eye.
Surely I deserve some credit
for your great fortune, don't I?
The white silk or the poisoned wine.
Choose for yourself.
Meng Ting Hui, you liar!
You will die a terrible death!
Huxiao Gang will not let you off!
I will haunt you even as a ghost!
I'm just worried they will not dare to come.
For those who have harmed me,
I will not let a single one of them go.
[The Tiger's Roar Stirs the Wind]
Are the women at Nuanxiang Pavilion
not enough for you?
Master, I was wrong.
Dong Shou Cai
has committed suicide out of fear.
Rest assured. He didn't breathe a word
about us.
Master.
Brother. Brother.
I was wrong, brother.
Brother, I was truly wrong.
Spare me, brother.
Brother!
Is this your first day in the business?
That little wretch has already sold you out.
Brother, I was truly blinded by that wretch.
But my only thought was to find Meng Ting Hui
to help vent Master's anger.
Master...
- Get up!
- Brother.
Blinded by lust!
Played for a fool!
And you say you were helping Master?
In life, fear no court official.
In death, fear no King of Hell.
Master.
You are even more domineering than I am.
Master, spare my life!
Get over here!
Brother!
- I am your own brother!
- Shut up!
I do not want to die!
I am your own brother!
Brother! Brother!
Master,
he'll carry this punishment with him.
I beg you, Master,
just let him stay and continue serving
to atone for his sins.
It took our Huxiao Gang
ten years of hard work
to build this foundation in the capital.
Now, because of his actions alone,
we are being hunted
by the entire city's soldiers,
and it even alarmed His Majesty.
If we did not have people in the court,
the entire Huxiao Gang
would be buried with you!
No, Master!
I failed to teach him properly.
Master,
considering we've followed you
for over ten years,
please spare his life.
I beg you.
Behave yourselves these days.
Do not cause any more trouble.
Yes.
Thank you for sparing him.
Get lost.
[The imperial court is hunting Huxiao Gang.
Everyone must be extremely discreet]
Master.
Sit.
Your brother...
He is fine. Lost a chunk of flesh,
but no damage to the bone.
He'll live.
Keep a tight watch on him.
The imperial court is pressing hard.
He has an impatient temper.
If he stirs up trouble again,
he won't be so lucky.
Rest assured, Master.
If he is this reckless again,
no need for the gang rules.
I'll break his legs myself.
I had Old Li make this for you.
I do not know if it fits.
Do not be so impulsive again.
Miss Meng,
you look much better than a few days ago.
You still need more rest.
I have rested for many days.
I want to go out for a walk.
I've heard the Imperial Garden is stunning.
Does His Majesty often go there?
In his spare time after reviewing memorials,
he occasionally takes a brief rest there.
Miss Meng, I'll take my leave.
My body has already recovered.
The Palace Exam is coming soon.
I must seize the opportunity before me.
This was my mother's favorite flower.
What a pity.
Rotten soil nurtures no good flowers.
Huang Bo, go and get another new seedling.
Yes.
Grand Tutor, I summoned you today
to discuss a matter.
I wish to establish the Censorate,
independent from the two chancellors
and six ministries.
Above, it can supervise all officials,
and below, it can eradicate evil,
reporting directly to my ear.
Your Majesty.
Here.
If Your Majesty wishes
to cultivate new talent,
although these young seedlings
are free of pests,
their roots are too shallow
to weather the storm.
The Censorate?
Is Huiyuan Meng still recuperating
in the palace?
Of course. His Majesty feels for beauty.
With imperial physicians and tonics,
one could say it is the utmost care.
Now, Lord Xu is watching
the fallout from the Imperial Exam for Women.
Now Your Majesty brings Huiyuan Meng back.
I'm afraid...
Bringing in new scholars
is meant to counter Lord Xu.
It was the Ministry of Rites' negligence
that caused Huiyuan Meng such suffering.
The Palace Exam is imminent.
I am merely hoping she can recover soon
and prepare with peace of mind.
Your Majesty,
if Huiyuan Meng stays in the palace too long,
it will invite gossip.
Lord Xu's faction is eyeing us covetously.
If they make a big fuss over this,
it may harm Your Majesty's name.
It'll also jeopardize Miss Meng's future.
You are absolutely right.
Then summon the imperial physician
to examine Huiyuan Meng again.
If she's well,
send her out of the palace immediately.
The world is dark and murky,
and the night is endless.
The heavens are unkind,
and tears wet my robes.
Your Majesty, should I stop her?
Let her vent.
Fierce winds and sudden rain,
what is there to fear?
I shall be the sword that slays the fiends.
Huiyuan Meng's temperament
carries the wildness of the Shazhou people.
Your Majesty did not see,
but she was formidable in interrogation too.
In just a moment, Jiang Mei Er confessed.
She is never simple to begin with.
This blow will only make her
more resolute and unhesitating.
Her next step
will be to find herself
a tree to lean on, I suppose.
Your Majesty,
Huiyuan Meng has just recovered.
If she gets rained on, she might fall ill
and miss the Palace Exam.
How about I take Huiyuan Meng back first?
Why torture yourself?
He Du.
Your Majesty, rest assured,
Huiyuan Meng just caught a chill.
It's nothing serious.
Once she sobers up,
a dose of cold medicine will cure her.
You may leave now.
Yes.
Your Majesty,
since she's fine,
we should head back now,
as it's getting late.
He Du.
No need for formalities.
No, you are the emperor.
I must pay my respects.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
You may leave for now.
- Your Majesty--
- I know what I'm doing.
I never imagined that He Du,
the one who faced death with me in Shazhou,
would actually be the emperor.
That day at the Capital Prefectural Office,
if Your Majesty had not appeared in time,
I'm afraid
I wouldn't even be left in one piece.
Thank you, Your Majesty, for saving my life.
I do not know how to repay you.
The Imperial Exam fraud
and the Ministry of Rites' negligence
are my failing.
You have suffered.
If you truly wish to repay me,
do not ruin your own health any longer.
Do well in the exam.
I remember in Shazhou,
Your Majesty gave me a chance,
but I rejected Your Majesty's kind offer.
Now I understand.
In this man-eat-man world,
being aloof and righteous
can cost one their life.
I am so afraid,
afraid that one day, even Your Majesty
will not be able to protect me.